Guide to the Records of the Office of the Chancellor/Executive Vice President (Borowitz) RG.6.0.7
New York University Archives
- Series VI: Governance
  - University Senate Committees, Misc, May 1974-Jan 1977 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - University Senate Committees, Misc, Apr 1971-Apr 1973 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - University Senate Committees, Misc, Oct 1970-Mar 1971 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - University Senate Committees, Organization and Governance, Oct 1976-Feb 1977 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - University Senate Committees, Organization and Governance, Oct 1974-May 1976 (Box 40, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Government Relations
  This series of 2.91 linear feet represents university administration's relationships and transactions with federal, state, and local government entities. As noted above in another context, aspects of these relationships can be found as well in Box 5, folders 6-9, Box 6, folders 8-12, Box 7, folders 11-14, and Box 8, folders 1-3.
  Many of the interactions at the federal level are routine. Included in these records though are materials covering planning for, requesting, negotiating, receiving, and administering a nationally competitive Science Development Grant from the National Science Foundation for the improvement of the physics and psychology departments in the Faculty of Arts and Science, Box 41, folders 7-12, through Box 43, folder 4.
  NYU received a total of $6,100,000 for this project, $4,560,000 in 6/69 and $1,600,000 in supplemental funds, 6/72. Among these documents are minutes of an internal Science Development Committee which indicate the struggle for an institutional strategy, Box 43, folder 1, correspondence from President Hester to NSF officials candidly describing the University's general situation, 4/9/74, 4/13/72 and 4/5/72, (the latter letter also discusses the grant's impact on the University, this project got underway at the time of great financial difficulties and was affected in a variety of ways by those difficulties), proposals (1967, 1972) following folder 2, annual reports, and the University's final report on this grant, Box 41, folder 7.
  The local government material is extremely limited and routine. Within the modest collection concerned with the University's relations with the City University of New York, a Borowitz letter, 7/11/73, Box 43, folder 9, probably sums up the nature of the relationship. In contrast, the University's dealings with New York State, and most particularly the State Education Department, are extensive.
  NYU's financial difficulties and the search for remedies brought it into close touch with the Department and its leadership during this period. Notable documents include university reports on use of Aid/Bundy funds, Box 44, folders 9-10, an address by Dr. Hester to the Regents' Seventh Annual Conference, 2/18/71, its submission for the CICU State Master Plan for Higher Education 1972, Box 45, folder 6, Professor Arnold Goren's commentary on a Regents Regional Coordinating Council Executive Committee meeting 7/18/75, an 11/71 NYSED report: "NYU: A Major Private Institution in Trouble A Report to the Board of Regents," Box 46, folder 3, NYU 5 Year Financial Plan(9/72-8/77), Box 46, folder 4, NYU 1976 Master Plan, Box 46, folder 11.
  - University Senate Committees, Organization and Governance, Jan 1971-Mar 1973 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - University Senate Committees, Tenure, Feb 1970-Dec 1975 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Health, Education, and Welfare, Oct 1974-Dec 1976 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Health, Education, and Welfare, Oct 1973-Aug 1974 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Health, Education, and Welfare, Mar 1973-Aug 1973 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Health, Education, and Welfare, Feb 1968-Dec 1972 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224978 2
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Misc, Nov 1974-Mar 1977 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Misc, Nov 1971-Jun 1974 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Endowment for the Humanities, Oct 1972-Oct 1976 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation, Jan 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation, May 1972-Aug 1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Nov 1976-Nov 1977 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Nov 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Apr 1975-Oct 1975 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Jan 1975-Mar 1975 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Jan 1974-Dec 1974 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Sep 1972-Dec 1973 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Jan 1972-Aug 1972 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224979 0
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Nov 1971-Dec 1971 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Sep 1971-Oct 1971 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Sep 1970-Aug 1971 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant, Sep 1969-Jun 1970 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Proposal, Jan 1968-Jul 1969 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Proposal, Aug 1966-Dec 1967 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant - Psychology Work papers, Etc., Jan 1967-Dec 1967 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Proposal - Science Development Committee, Dec 1966-Jun 1967 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224980 8
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, National Science Foundation Science Development Grant - Impact Evaluation, Sep 1971-May 1972 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - A Proposal for a University Science Development Supplementary Grant Submitted to the National Science Foundation, Feb 1972 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - A Proposal for Support of the Science Center at Washington Square (Phase I Physics & Psychology) Submitted Under the University Science Development Program National Science Foundation December, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Federal Departments and Agencies, Legislation, Misc, Mar 1970-Sep 1975 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - New York City, City, Feb 1973-Nov 1973 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - New York City, City University, Sep 1975-Mar 1977 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - New York City, City University, Jan 1974-Apr 1975 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - New York City, City University, Mar 1973-Dec 1973 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - New York City, City University, Oct 1971-Dec 1972 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - New York State Education Department, Jul 1976-Mar 1977 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224981 6
  - New York State Education Department, Jan 1976-Jun 1976 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - New York State Education Department, Aug 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - New York State Education Department, Feb 1975-Apr 1975 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - New York State Education Department, Jun 1974-Nov 1974 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - New York State Education Department, Jul 1973-May 1974 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - New York State Education Department, Sep 1972-Jun 1973 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - New York State Education Department, Jan 1971-May 1972 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - New York State Education Department, Bundy Legislation/AID, Oct 1972-Sep 1976 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - New York State Education Department, Bundy Legislation/AID, Mar 1969-Aug 1972 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - New York State Education Department, Correspondence: Program Registration Approvals, Jun 1971-Dec 1976 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - New York State Education Department, DA Degree, Apr 1975-Jan 1976 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - New York State Education Department, Doctoral Project, Oct 1974-Jan 1975 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - New York State Education Department, HEOP, Jan 1973-May 1976 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - New York State Education Department, HEOP, Apr 1971-Jun 1972 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - New York State Education Department, Press Releases, Announcements, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224982 4
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Annual Trustee Conferences, Feb 1970-Mar 5, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: External Degree, Nov 1971-Sep 1974 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Master Plan for Higher Education 1976, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Master Plan for Higher Education 1972, Jun 1972-Dec 1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Master Plan for Higher Education 1972, Jan 1972-Apr 1972 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Oct 1975-Apr 1976 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Jul 1975-Sep 1975 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, May 1975-Jun 1975 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Mar 1975-Apr 1975 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Jan 1975-Feb 1975 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Nov 1974-Dec 1974 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Oct 1974 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Jun 1972-Sep 1974 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224983 2
  - New York State Education Department, Regents: Regional Coordinating Council, Proposed Relocating of Baruch College, Jul 1972-Nov 1972 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - New York State Education Department, Report: New York University: A Major Private Institution in Trouble, Nov 1971-Dec 1971 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - New York State Education Department, Reports: New York University Five Year Plan for the Period 9/72 - 8/77, Sep 1972-Aug 1977 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - New York State Education Department, Reports and Recommendations Concerning Privately Operated Schools of Dentistry in New York State, Jan 1975-Mar 1975 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Addendum: Reports Significant to New York University Interest
  - New York State Energy Research and Development Authority, Jun 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - New York State, Legislation, Oct 1972-Apr 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - New York State, Legislation, Mar 1971-Aug 1972 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - New York State, Legislative Committees, Nov 1973-Aug 1975 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - New York State, Misc, Mar 1970-Jun 1976 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - New York State, New York University Master Plan 1976, Apr 1976 (Box 46, Folder 11)
- Series VIII: Institutional Advancement
  This series of 2.5 linear feet is something of an alphabetical, and topical, smorgasbord, beginning with Academic Change, Box 47, folder 1, and finishing with Women's Studies, Box 52, folder 26. It represents in the main a collection whose organizing principle might be characterized as "Is There Anything Here for Us?" Material is commonly in the form of newspaper, journal and news service clippings. Much of the content was identified in, or in the case of reports, prepared in the office of the Vice President for Academic Planning and Services.
  One interesting assemblage, Box 49, folders 11-18, is material enabling the tracking of the development and outcomes of a University Goals Conference convened by Dr. Hester and titled "New York University 1981." The concluding "Goals Statement," discussed and amended by the University Senate, 10/31/75, is located in Box 49, folder 11. It reflects upon the decade the University emerged from in 1974 and projects its ambitions and goals for the decade ahead. By contrast, a copy of a "Report for the Decade Ahead 1964-1973," by Dr. Hester, found in Box 49, folder 18, projects forward from the pre-crisis vantage point of 1964.
  - New York State, Task Force on Higher Education: Misc, Nov 1971-Mar 1975 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - New York State, Temporary Commission on Campus Unrest, Sep 1972 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - New York State, State University of New York (SUNY), Aug 1972-Oct 1975 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Academic Change, Apr 1970-Feb 1974 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224984 0
  - Adult Education, Lifelong Learning, May 1970-Jan 1975 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Accountability, Aug 1973 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Arts Administration Advisory Committee, Feb 1974-Jan 1976 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Articulation - Joint Degrees, Aug 1970-Oct 1975 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Atlantis Group, Jul 1974-Sep 1974 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Calendar Revision, Sep 1973-Jan 1977 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Calendar Revision, Oct 1971-May 1973 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Calendar Revision, Jan 1970-Apr 1971 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Calendar Revision, Quarter System, Oct 1967-Jan 1968 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Campus Unrest, Sep 1970-Jun 1972 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Campus Unrest, May 1968-Jul 1970 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Careers, Jobs, Job Market, Jan 1971-Jan 1976 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Community Colleges, Junior Colleges, Mar 1970-Sep 1974 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Competency-Based Education, Dec 1973 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Consortia, Inter-institutional Cooperation, Oct 1970-Mar 1974 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Cooperative Education, Jun 1972-Nov 1975 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Course Evaluation, Correspondence, Press, Mar 1975-Oct 1975 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Course Evaluation, Correspondence, Press, Jan 1974-Feb 1975 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Course Evaluation, Correspondence, Press, Oct 1970-Dec 1973 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224985 7
  - Course Evaluation, Literature, Jan 1974-Aug 1975 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Course Evaluation, Literature, 1969-Nov 1973 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Course Evaluation, Procedure, Sep 1973-Sep 1975 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Courses by Magazine, Oct 1973-Feb 1976 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Courses by Newspaper, Feb 1974 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Courses on Tape, Nov 1972-Jun 1975 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Credit for Non-Traditional Education Experience, Jan 1971-Mar 1974 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Credit Practices and Quality Control, Study Group on, Oct 1974-May 1975 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Critical Reviews, Apr 1969-Jan 1971 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum (Incl. Interdisciplinary, Task Force, Intensive, Academic Thrust), Jan 1972-Jan 1974 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum (Incl. Interdisciplinary, Task Force, Intensive, Academic Thrust), Sep 1970-Nov 1971 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum (Incl. Interdisciplinary, Task Force, Intensive), Sep 1969-Aug 1970 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Degrees, Contracts, Certificates, Sep 1971-May 1973 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Degrees, Contracts, Certificates, Jan 1970-Jul 1971 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Degree Programs at NYU, Aug 1972, Jan 1975 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Educational Technology, Mar 1971-Apr 1974 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Education by Business, Dec 1971, Dec 1972, Jan 1975 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Environmental Studies, Ecology, Jan 1970-Nov 1971 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Equality in Higher Education, Mar 1970-Feb 1971 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Evaluation of Programs, Jun 1973 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224986 5
  - External Degrees, May 1970-Mar 1976 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Experimental Programs, Colleges, Apr 1970-Jan 1973 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Extra-Curricular Activities Leisure, Feb 1969-May 1972 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Development, 1975 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Finances of Universities, Sep 1971-Sep 1974 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Finances of Universities, Sep 1969-Jul 1971 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Futuristics Program, Jan 1973-Oct 1976 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - General Education (Papers), 1973 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - General Statements on Higher Education, Apr 1970-Feb 1972, Feb 1975 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Jul 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Sep 1974-Jun 1975 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Mar 1974-Jul 1974 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Feb 1974 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Jan 1974 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Nov 1973-Dec 1973 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Sep 1973-Oct 1973 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Goals Conference "New York University 1981", Mar 1964, Apr 1973-Aug 1973 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Grading, Sep 1970-Jun 1975 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224987 3
  - Grading, 1968-Aug 1970 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Education, Sep 1971-Jul 1974 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Education, Feb 1970-Jan 1971 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Guidance, Counseling, Advisement, Ombudsman, Mar 1969-Jun 1974 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Guidelines for Federal Funding, Misc, 1973-1976 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Handicapped Students, Aug 1974 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Health Services, Apr 1970 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Honors Program, Jun 1970-Oct 1972 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Independent Study, Mar 1970-Sep 1971 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Innovations, Varied: Lists, Sep 1970-Feb 1975 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Innovations, Varied: Lists, Dec 1969-Aug 1970 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Innovative Flexibility, Jan 1970-Dec 1970 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Institutional Facilities, Mar 1970 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Institutional Planning, Programmed Budgeting, May 1969-Feb 1972 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Institutional Research, Nov 1970-Jun 1971 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Intercollegiate Press Bulletins, Mar 1976 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Interdisciplinary Programs, Apr 1974 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - International Studies, Nov 1970-Dec 1972 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Language Studies, Apr 1970-Apr 1973 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Liberal Arts Requirements, Dec 1975 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Liberal Studies MA, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Libraries, Aug 1970-Mar 1974 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Life Experience Credit Literature, Nov 1974-Mar 1975 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Marketing in Higher Education, Sep 1973 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Medical Education & Pre-Med, Apr 1973-Jun 1974 (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Military Research, Feb 1970-Jul 1970 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Minority Interests, Disadvantaged, Oct 1970-Mar 1974 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - National Trends, Statistics, Oct 1972-May 1974 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - National Trends, Statistics, May 1969-Oct 1971 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - New Markets in Higher Education, undated (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - New York Management Center, Jul 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 32)
  - Non-Campus Programs, Sep 1971 (Box 50, Folder 33)
  - Non-Uniformity Studies, Jan 1973-Dec 1973 (Box 50, Folder 34)
  - Non-Uniformity Studies, May 1961-Dec 1972 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224988 1
  - Non-Western Studies, Third World Studies, Jan 1970-Oct 1970 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Off-Campus Programs, Jul 1975 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Open University, Apr 1969-May 1975 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - "Other" Studies, Commissions, Reports, Aug 1970-Oct 1973 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Overseas Programs, Study Group on, Nov 1974-Mar 1976 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Philosophical Views on the University, on Education, Jan 1970-Apr 1974 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Pre-Professional Education, Sep 1970 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Private vs. Public Institutions of Higher Education, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Professional Education, Oct 1970-Jul 1974 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Project Change in Liberal Education, Nov 1973-Jun 1974 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Proposals for Funding, Misc, Nov 1976 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Proposals for Funding, Misc, Feb 1976-Mar 1976 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Proposals for Funding, Misc, Jan 1976 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Proposals for Funding, Misc, Jul 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Proposals for Funding, Misc, Jun 1972-Dec 1975 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Proposals for Funding, Misc, Jun 1971-Mar 1972 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Proposals for NYU, May 1973-Apr 1976 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    barcode: 3 1142 04224989 9
  - Proposals Within NYU, Dec 1975 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Radicalism, Mar 1970-Oct 1970 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Relations with Prisons, Apr 1972-Nov 1972 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Remedial Education, Higher Education Opportunity Programs, Apr 1970-Jan 1974 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Research Projects, Oct 1969-Mar 1971 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Research Services, Feb 1976-Apr 1976 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Secondary School/College Articulation, Dec 1971-Mar 1976 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Secondary School Students, Preparation of, Sep 1970-Feb 1975 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Relations with Secondary Schools, Jun 1970-Dec 1974 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Seminars, Feb 1970 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Senior Colleges, Mar 1972 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Spence Women's Institute, Dec 1973-Jan 1974 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Summer Programs, Oct 1973 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Teaching and Learning, Nov 1973-Mar 1975 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Testing, Placement, Sep 1973-Oct 1974 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Training of Teachers, Mar 1969-Dec 1972 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - University Structure (Including Depts, Cluster Colleges), Nov 1970-Dec 1972 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - University Structure (Including Depts, Cluster Colleges), Apr 1970-Nov 1970 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Urban Studies, Community Orientation, Oct 1972-May 1973 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Urban Studies, Community Orientation, Sep 1971-Jul 1972 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Urban Studies, Community Orientation, Sep 1970-Jun 1971 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Urban Studies, Community Orientation, Feb 1970-Jul 1970 (Box 52, Folder 23)
- Series IX: Personnel
  This series is one linear foot. Movement toward standards defining and governing members of the various communities of people who constitute the University appears in these records. Documentation of the University's emerging Affirmative Action Program fills all of Boxes 53 and 54, and folders 1-2 in Box 55. Items pertinent to the development of comprehensive benefits programs for faculty, management and staff is contained in Box 55, folders 5-19 and Box 56, folders 1-4.
  Material concerned with attempts to define middle management personnel and standardize their conditions of employment can be reviewed in Box 56, folders 12-13. Similar efforts directed toward those employees known as Professional Research Personnel, can be seen in Box 56, folder 14. The records covering the faculty unionization drive referred to above were contained within this series when it was received in the Archives; these materials were transferred to Mss Collection RG 14 B1. General matters relating to recruitment, retirement, sabbaticals, severance, tenure, terminations and resignations, and tuition remission are also addressed within the contents of this series. Again, material pertaining to individual cases was discarded.
  - Urban Studies, Community Orientation, Jan 1969-Feb 1969 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Vocational Education, Paraprofessional, Technical, Jan 1970-Dec 1971 (Box 52, Folder 25)